Sinners?
罪人？
We are?
我們是罪人？
Lykos?
黎可斯？
Dear me, it's already here.
…已經來了…
Chakuro...
查克羅…
I'm sorry.
對不起
Translator
翻
ssnake
譯
静寂よ　旋律よ　儚き印よ
ssnake
Silence and melody, and the transient lives of Shirushi
静寂よ　旋律よ　儚き印よ
Timing
時 間 軸
zwc1991
zwc1991
砂上にこの地に　生き続けたのなら
砂上にこの地に　生き続けたのなら
If you have been living on the land, on the sea of sand
如果是在這沙海之上  生活下去
罪を纏う世界から　鯨の歌を聴いた…
罪を纏う世界から　鯨の歌を聴いた…
In a sinned world, we have heard the whale's lied
在罪業重重的世界裡  我們曾側耳傾聽鯨魚的歌唱…
運命を　感情を　抱くべき子たちよ
運命を　感情を　抱くべき子たちよ
Our fate and our emotions, my beloved children
不論命運  還是感情  親愛的孩子們喲
さ  き
さ  き
その先へ　その未来へ
その先へ　その未来へ
Towards the future, go ahead
向著未來  向著前方
導かれたのなら
導かれたのなら
If you can be our guide
只要有你指引前路
幾千の声　空想の地へ
幾千の声　空想の地へ
Thousands of words, leaving for the fantasy lands
萬千寄語  向著空想的彼岸
舵を切って行こうとした
舵を切って行こうとした
Steering towards the opposite
相信信念調轉方向
バラード
バラード
幾千の声　砂の海の譚歌
幾千の声　砂の海の譚歌
Thousands of songs, they are the ballads of the sea of sand
萬千歡聲  是沙海的歌謠
F
雪 飄 工 作 室
L
雪 飄 工 作 室
Help!
救救我！
Help me!
來人啊！
Everybody listen!
大家聽好！
Enter the building as soon as possible!
趕快躲到房子裡去
Taisha-sama!
台霞姐姐！
Move!
動作快！
Then flee to the specialized building!
然後到專門樓棟裡避難
Huh?
嗯？
What's up?
發生什麼事了嗎？
It's strange.
狀況好奇怪
What's hell there? Hey.
在吵鬧什麼呢 到底
Dunno.
鬼知道
Hey.
喲
See that guy, he's wearing something strange.
瞧 怎麼回事 那身行頭
Isn't he a fellow of the girl in that island?
是那個島上的女的的同夥吧
Let's knock him over.
要不抓起來看看
Hey, you.
喂 你這小子！
Be here.
給我過來一下
We wanna get to the world outside...
我們啊 想去外面的世界逛逛
What?
嗯？
Whah?
哎
Buki!
布奇！
Hey Bukiii!
喂 布奇！
Hey.
喂
What's up?
搞什麼啊
Let me out, it's strange outside.
放我出去 外面情況不對勁
Hurt...
痛…
Sami.
莎米
The angle of death
殺戮的天使
had torn our paradise to bits
用他偌大的指甲
with his huge claw.
撕碎了我們的樂園
Sami, we have to run away.
莎米 快逃…
I'll never do this again.
就只今天這一次哦
Sami, you're not heavy at all.
莎米 你一點也不重的
You are as light as 3 years ago.
和三年前幾乎一樣
Sorry for making fun with you yesterday.
昨天只是開個玩笑 對不起了
Sami...
莎米…
Finally the judgment is passed on us.
終於做出審判了嗎
Sami and Chakuro are still in the farm!
莎米和查克羅他們還在農園
It's wrong...
…搞錯了…
These people...
這些人
They are not the sinners who should perish!
並不是應該滅絕的罪人！
What's the hell is that?
怎麼回事 這是…
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
In the mission of annihilating the sinners of the whale,
關於殲滅鯨的罪人這一任務
the most important thing is to take records.
最重要的 是要做好記錄
We need to show the end of them, the heretic,
要以他們這些異端的末路為戒
to the people in our empire...
向我國 不
No, but to point out the path that all mankind in the world should take.
要向全世界的人類指明康莊大道
Record it scrupulously.
必須詳盡地做好記錄
Lykos?
黎可斯？
No you can't.
不行
Wait!
等等
I have no choice but to fight.
我必須要戰鬥
Even if... it means that I have to betray that person.
哪怕… 要背叛那個人
Hey you.
你們…
Suo-sama.
蘇澳哥哥
Are you OK?
沒事吧？
Yes.
沒事
But there are still injured people in the farm.
但是 農園裡還有受傷的人…
Suo-sama.
蘇澳哥哥
Everybody...
大家…
Suo,
蘇澳
please listen calmly.
聽了以後 請你一定要鎮定
It seems Taisha-sama...
台霞姐姐她…
has died...
好像過世了…
The presbytery keeps silence in such a situation.
關於這個事態 長老會保持沉默
Why... why we have to face this tragedy?
為什麼 我們會遭遇這種事情
Shinono-sama...
希諾諾姐姐…
Please gather together in the central square,
請讓大家在中央廣場集合
and ask the vigilante group to protect everybody.
由警備團保護大家
As far as they are human,
對方也是人類才對吧
they should not allow such violence.
這樣的暴行 又怎麼能容許
Since the presbytery doesn't take a move,
既然長老會沒有行動
I will solve it by negotiation!
就讓我跟他們交涉來解決！
Damn! You're making fool of us.
畜生 敢瞧不起我們
Take this, asshole!
別小看我們 該死的！
Stop!
不要！
Aijiro!
艾吉洛！
No, it's impossible.
不…不行啊
sentikinesis
thymia
They're using their thymia...
這些傢伙的情念力的用法
in a murderer way.
完全是殺人的手法
They're demons! It's crazy!
他們是鬼啊 不正常啊！
S... stop that shit!
別 別開玩笑了
Keep away! If you get any closer!
不許你們 再靠近了！
Nibi
尼比
Oni!
歐尼！
Oni! Buki and Aijiro died!
歐尼！ 布奇和艾吉洛死了
They got killed!
被他們殺死的！
So that's it...
…這麼回事嗎
That is the world we have longed for, outside the sea of sand,
我跟這些人一直憧憬著的沙海之外
where the masked guys can trample our dream easily.
是一個讓看不見臉的傢伙們 輕易踐踏我們的夢想
So that is the world!
這樣的世界嗎
Oni!
歐尼！
I don't care anymore...
夠了…
I care no more...
這樣的世界…
about that world!
再也無所謂了！
So we have everybody here?
這就是所有人了嗎
Suo-sama!
蘇澳哥哥！
I'm Ginshu from the vigilante group.
我是警備團的銀淑
Our task is to protect the peace of mud whale.
我們警備團的任務是保護泥鯨的和平與穩定
We should give them as good as we got!
被人搞了的話就一定要搞回去！
You should never kill the opposite.
不可以殺人
It's an endless circle if we return violence to violence.
以暴制暴是沒有盡頭的
There is no reason for us to be attacked.
我們沒有理由遭到攻擊
There must be something misunderstood.
事態發展至此一定有什麼誤會
We are solving this misunderstanding.
我們要去解除這個誤會
I believe Taisha-sama would solve it in this manner.
台霞姐姐的話 一定會這麼做的
Man...
哇…
Taisha-sama...
台霞姐姐…
Is it fine?
這樣就好了嗎…
Is this the only way, we can deal with it?
我們只能這麼做嗎…
No more I wanna see.
什麼都不想看
Sami, it's fine right?
莎米…已經夠了吧
Let's close our eyes together, like this.
就這樣一起瞑目吧
Then I don't have to see stuffs disgusting me any more, right?
這樣…就再也不用看那些討厭的東西了吧
Chakuro!
查克羅！
Where's our brother?
哥哥呢？
Kids...
小傢伙們…
Ah, wait!
啊… 等等
Stop it!
住手！
Don't do anything with the kids, please.
求求你別對小傢伙做什麼
I beg you...
拜託…
S... STOP!!
住… 住手！
Stop it!
住手啊
Stop it please!
讓你住手啊！
The same skin color with Lykos...
和黎可斯一樣的膚色
Brother!
哥哥！
You idiot!
笨蛋 你們這些…
Chakuro!
查克羅！
Chakuro run away!
查克羅 快逃！
Don't touch Sami!
不許碰莎米！
Keep out!
不許靠近！
Stop.
住手
She is...
這個人是——
So you have survived.
您還活著啊
νοῦς
νοῦς
λύκος
λύκος
It's said that Lykos the nous
魂形「黎可斯」
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
received an assault during its way to the annihilation of Fallaina,
在前往法萊那殲滅作戰的途中遭到襲擊
and nobody survived.
據報是全軍覆沒
Is there any other survival?
還有其他生還者嗎？
Hey, what the hell is it?
喂 這是怎麼回事啊
Shhh.
噓
This way.
請來這邊
σκύλος
σκύλος
Let's return to Skulax.
請回到斯奇洛斯上
Leave me alone.
放開我
I won't return to you.
我不會回到你們那裡去
νοῦς
νοῦς
You must get disturbed after leaving the control of nous.
您脫離魂形的控制以後失去理智了嗎？
After all, you are the younger sister
您可是法萊那殲滅作戰總指揮官的
of the general commander of the annihilation of Fallaina.
妹妹
It's nothing to do with my brother!
我跟哥哥已經沒關係了！
Has he searched me for a single time?
哥哥他有搜救過我嗎？
Has he told my parents about my potential death?
有向父母報告我生死未卜嗎？
Even if I return to the empire,
我就算回到祖國
I'm just a puppet with neither mind nor name!
也只是一個不存心智沒有名字的傀儡！
Wait a moment, please.
請您等等
αράχνη
αράχνη
Tell Arakhne, captain of Skulax.
通報斯奇洛斯的阿拉弗尼司令
Lykos...
黎可斯
Who...
你…
Who are you?
你是誰？
Answer me.
回答我
He has the same skin color with you...
這傢伙也跟你是一樣的膚色…
Hey hey hey!
喂喂喂～
How dare you lose it, rubbish!
誰讓你被幹掉的 人渣！
λύκος
λύκος
No. 32 of Lykos!
「黎可斯」32號！
You are alive!
你還活著啊
λιοντάρι
λιοντάρι
Ryotari...
柳達理…
You were on Skulax?
你在斯奇洛斯上啊
I heard that Lykos had been wiped out, I was worried.
聽說「黎可斯」全軍覆沒 我可擔心了
You don't even have such a mind.
你根本沒有這樣的心智
Bingo!
答對了～
There's no time for me to worry you!
哪有空擔心你啊！
I was sent to the massacre!
這不是被派遣到大屠殺的現場來了嗎
I was looking forward it all my heart that I could care nothing else!
滿心期待滿心期待 哪還會考慮別的事情！
Fallaina is the best, the paradise!
法萊那是最棒的樂園啊！
Full of prey, no resistance!
到處都是不會抵抗的獵物
See!
瞧啊
I can even kill such a cute girl!
這～麼可愛的小姑娘都能隨便弄死
Don't touch Sami!
不許碰莎米！
Cry... Crying!
哭…哭了
This guy is crying!
這傢伙哭了！
I seldom see anyone crying!
會哭的傢伙可少見了
I wanna make you cry more!
還想讓你哭得更厲害
I wanna break you more!
想讓你壞得更厲害
I wanna kill...
想讓你死得更…
Ryotari,
柳達理！
I won't let you do harm to him.
不許對那孩子出手！
No. 32...
32號…
Why interrupt me?
為什麼要搗亂
You mean I can kill you too?
是說你也能讓我殺死嗎
It's Skulax.
斯奇洛斯
νοῦς
νοῦς
λύκος
λύκος
We have secured Lykos ths nous.
我們已經得到魂形「黎可斯」
The soldiers should return.
各部隊立刻返回
Chakuro!
查克羅！
Lion guy, we finished today.
獅子頭 今天到此為止了
Get back.
回去了
Hey what about this guy?
喂 這傢伙要怎麼辦
Shouldn't we bring her back?
得帶回去吧
No, I won't return!
不要 我不回去！
Hah?
什麼？
You know it's impossible.
這怎麼可能
What're you going to do in Fallaina at all?
說到底 你要在法萊那上幹什麼
All the guys here will die after all.
這裡的傢伙們 早晚都要去死的
Leave me!
放開我
Hey you...
你啊…
Listen to me, the idiots over there.
那邊的小笨蛋們
Listen, listen!
傳話 傳話～
όρκα
όρκα
It's the pierrot of general commander Orca.
那是奧爾卡總司令的小丑
We leave No. 32 in Fallaina.
32號就這麼留在法萊那
The general commander said
總司令說要讓妹妹
we shall treat his younger sister as a sample
φάλαινα
We should call her
從今以後對她的稱呼
Sample No. 4 of Skulax from now on.
變更為斯奇洛斯樣本4號
That's all!
這麼說的～
How... How cruel he is!
好…好無情啊
That's what he did after knowing his younger sister is still alive!
明明發現本以為死掉了的妹妹還活著
Hey! Sample No. 4!
喂 樣本4號
You are abandoned by your bro!
你啊 被哥哥拋棄了！
Go back, go back.
回家家 回家家
Hey, pick me up!
喂 帶我一個
I will be here again, Sample No. 4!
我還會來的 樣品4號
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
I wanna see how strange you will be after get influenced by Fallaina!
到那時候 讓我欣賞欣賞被法萊那玩壞的你的樣子
You have a name, don't you?
名字的話你有的呀
Λύκος
λύκος
Lykos, embroidered on your clothes.
你衣服上繡著「黎可斯」
όρκα
όρκα
Orca-sama.
奧爾卡司令
Do you remember me?
您還記得我嗎？
Your sister's friend.
我是您妹妹的朋友
Making your sister a guinea pig, didn't you be too cruel?
把妹妹當作小白鼠 您未免有些太殘酷了吧
I have heard that if you succeed in this operation,
據說啊 您要是這次作戰取得成功
you will be appointed as the governor of a state.
就能當上一州的總督了呢
That is, to put it simply,
這不是
you are sacrificing your sister for your career, right?
為了發達犧牲妹妹嗎
I don't want to move the empire.
我並不是要運作這個國家
My purpose is out of it.
我的目的別有所在
Taisha-sama...
台霞姐姐…
Oni!
歐尼！
What... Why you are in such a mess?
你…你這一身 是怎麼回事
Give me remedies.
給我藥
You are full of bloods, are you wounded?
這血…你受傷了嗎？
Remedies are for my friends.
藥是給伙伴的
After 7 days...
7天後…
What?
嗯？
They will come again.
那些傢伙還會再來的
Their purpose this time is the rescue of the ship where that girl was on.
這次的目的是回收那個女的乘的船
Next time will be the attack of mud whale.
說是下次才是襲擊泥鯨
How... How did you know that?
你…你怎麼知道這個的？
I made them tell me?
…逼他們說的
Ma... made them?
逼…逼他們說？
I killed them all except two.
就留了兩個活口 其他都殺了
You...
你…
The two guys are in the same age as us.
那兩個活口 都跟我們歲數差不多
Why you hit him?
為什麼要打他啊！
How you dare doing things such as torture...
拷問這種事情 虧你們做得…
For all of us, isn't it!
這不是為了大家好嗎！
Oni is doing nothing wrong.
歐尼什麼都沒做錯！
We will all be killed if Oni doesn't do this for us!
要是歐尼不做的話 大家都會被殺死！
You made Oni to do all the dirty stuffs...
髒活全都讓歐尼做了不說…
Enough.
夠了
Go, Kicha.
綺茶 我們走
Wa.. Hey, wait!
喂… 喂等一下
Stop doing things alone!
別瞎搞
Prisoners should be hold by the vigilante group...
俘虜要交給警備團…
Oh no, give them to me!
…啊不 交給我！
I only trust my friends.
我只信任我的伙伴
The funeral was held as early as the next day.
葬禮在第二天早早就舉辦了
Although it is forbidden to cry at the funeral,
雖然葬禮上是禁止哭泣的
we could not help but crying.
但我們 都沒能夠遵守
I was always... wanted to change the fate
我一直… 想要改變「印」的短命
of the short lives of Shirushi for you.
因為我無法忍耐
Since I can't bear it if Sami and others
莎米和大家先我一步而去
Even without leaving a single word...
…甚至一句話也沒能留下
I'm sorry.
對不起
I failed to protect Sami.
我沒能保護好莎米
It was a sunny day.
那一天晴空萬里
The sight of the sand burial was really beautiful.
沙葬的光景是那麼美麗
I would like to make it
如果世間會有如此悲傷的事情
the last sight of my life,
不如就讓這個景色
if I have to face such a sad thing in this world.
作為我在人世間
The third section
第 三 節
I Care No More about That World
第 三 節
I thought.
我那時是這麼想的
乾いた海の跡　望んで
乾いた海の跡　望んで
Staring into the trace of the dried sea
眺望昔日的大海
まだ見ぬ対岸を描く
まだ見ぬ対岸を描く
I will draw the other side I have never seen
描繪未知的彼岸
囚われの心のままなら
囚われの心のままなら
If you remain your heart in captivity
如果囚禁起心靈  一如過往
こんな傷みも知らずにいた
こんな傷みも知らずにいた
You may live without knowing the pain
又怎麼會經歷如此悲傷
美しい詞を告げたひと
美しい詞を告げたひと
The one who told the beautiful story
是誰講述起美好的希望
夜明けも待たずに
夜明けも待たずに
Can not wait for the dawn
讓我等不及黎明
果てのその先を泳ぐ
果てのその先を泳ぐ
Until beyond the end of world, I am swimming
向著天涯海角揚帆起航
虫の唄
虫の唄
Listen to the insects' song
徹夜蟲鳴
眠らず君と聞いた記憶
眠らず君と聞いた記憶
That night is our memory
回憶裡與你一起側耳傾聽
手を　ただ結んで
手を　ただ結んで
Just link hand in hand
只是雙手相牽
半色でも　遠い国でも
半色でも　遠い国でも
No matter it is twilight or a distant country
不論夕陽  還是遠方
短い一章に生まれた夢を
短い一章に生まれた夢を
Born in a short chapter
在這短暫蒼渺的一章裡
抱きしめに行こう
抱きしめに行こう
But let us go and embrace that dream
一起追逐夢想
The fourth section
第 四 節
We Shall Suicide in the Sand Together with the Mud Whale
讓 我 們 與 泥 鯨